Shelley McHardy Atlanta, Georgia

Phone: 404-405-4045 | Email: shellevmcq.dev@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/shelleymchardy</u>

GitHub: <u>github.com/shelleymcq</u> Portfolio: <u>www.shelleymcq.dev</u>

Software developer with a background in science education, motivated to leverage tech and teaching skills to create modern applications and experiences for learners and information seekers, and to make the web more beautiful and accessible.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Redux, TypeScript, Optimizely, Cypress

PROJECT SAMPLES

Smart Shopper| Repo: https://github.com/the-collab-lab/tcl-36-smart-shopping-list
Deployed: https://tcl-36-smart-shopping-list.web.app/home

- A shopping list app designed to learn how often you buy items and to keep you organized.
- As a member of a 4-person team with the Collab Lab, primary contributions were styling, displaying list items, and leading the team during the final two self-directed weeks of the project.
- Developed using React, Firebase, and Tailwindcss.

nommy | Repo: https://github.com/shellevmcq/nommy

- A platform to save your restaurant dining ideas and to get inspiration.
- As a member of a 5-person team, primary contributions were styling with react-bootstrap, testing and debugging, and deployment to heroku.
- Developed using the MERN stack, with JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Graphql, Apollo Server Express, MongoDB, and React.

EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Developer

6/2021 - 3/2023

Rightpoint (remote)

- Created scripts in nodeJS that automate tasks and save developers time.
- Implemented new features to React codebase such as list virtualization.
- Review PRs, fix bugs, CSS to match app design, git version control in an Azure DevOps repo.
- Wrote/updated documentation for team.
- BigCommerce certified.

Teaching Assistant & Mentor

11/2021 - 4/2022

2U, Georgia Tech Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp (online)

- Supported instructor and mentored students via zoom and slack.
- Managed course repo on Gitlab, review and grade student projects
- Assisted individual and student groups as they learned web development with JavaScript, APIs, various libraries, frameworks, and the MERN stack.

React Developer Apprenticeship

1/2022 - 3/2022

The Collab Lab (remote)

- Worked with a team of four to build a project using React, Tailwind CSS, and Firebase.
- Focused on collaboration based on Agile methodology, pair programming, code reviews, weekly retrospectives, and git version control.

Science Teacher

10/2010 - 5/2021

Gwinnett County Public Schools, Lawrenceville, GA

- Taught chemistry, forensics, and physical science to middle and high school students.
- Designed and presented workshops to teachers in topics ranging from building relationships with students to integrating technology in the classroom.

Chemistry Teacher & Curriculum Developer

8/2003 - 6/2010

Oakland Unified School District, Oakland, CA

- Taught chemistry to high school students.
- Served the county team to develop chemistry pacing guide and benchmark assessment, and as a new teacher mentor.

VOLUNTEER

The Collab Lab

the-collab-lab.codes Board Member, Career Lab Manager

Virtual Coffee

virtualcoffee.io Lunch & Learn Coordinator

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia

A 24-week intensive 2U program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, Jest, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, ReactJS, MVC, and MERN stack.

BA in Physical Sciences

University of California, Berkeley, California

Completed core courses in chemistry and physics, as well as electives in computer programming, nuclear energy, atmospheric chemistry, and environmental data analysis.